Hi!
Приветствую!
My name is Oleg Sadov.
Меня зовут Олег Садов.
I'm going to be your instructor for this course.
На этом урсе я буду вашим инструктором.
I've been involved in the Unix world more than 30 years ago and have been working with
В Unix-мир я погрузился более 30 лет назад,
Linux systems almost from the very beginning.
а с Linux системами работаю с момента их появления.
This is an Unix and Linux introductory course.
Этот курс является введением в Unix и Linux.
This course isn't about memorizing countless definitions and specifications or endlessly
В этом курсе мы не будем заниматься изучением бесчисленных определений и спецификаций,
learning how to keystroke.
или нерпреывно жать на кнопки.
Instead, we will try to understand the philosophy of systems and the reasons why existing technical
Вместо этого мы попытаемся понять общую философию систем
It will show you how such systems are organized, and demonstrate how to use them at an advanced
Мы увидим, как организованы такие системы и поймем как их использовать
level, which you will be able to practice on your own.
для своих нужд на продвинутом уровне.
In addition to the usual lectures, we have added additional materials called "Under the Hood".
В дополнение к обычным лекциям мы добавили дополнительные материалы под названием «Под капотом» ("Under the Hood").
This is not required for graduation checks, but understanding it does matter when interviewing
Знание этих материалов не будет оцениваться, но понимание моментов изложенных в них будет иметь значение
for a well-known company like Google or Facebook.
при собеседовании в какой-нибудь известной компании, такой как Google или Facebook.
In this course you will be introduced to reasons why open standards and the open source development
В этом курсе вы познакомитесь с причинами, по которым открытые стандарты и модель разработки с открытым исходным кодом
model are so important in today's computing environment.
так важны в современной компьютерной среде.
After completing this course, you will have a solid introduction to working with Unix/Linux
After completing this course, you will have a solid introduction to working with Unix/Linux
from the command line and a good understanding of principles how these systems work.
После завершения этого курса вы получите навык работы с Unix/Linux из командной строки и хорошее понимание принципов работы этих систем.
In applying these skills, you will be able to perform fundamental operational tasks,
При помощи этих навыков, вы сможете выполнять текущие рабочие задачи, независимо от того,
whether your Unix/Linux machine is in your hands or on a remote system across the Internet.
работаете вы с Unix/Linux на своём компьютере или в удаленной системе через Интернет.
And you will be ready to work with any UNIX-like system with an experienced user and move on
И вы будете готовы работать с любой UNIX-подобной системой на уровне опытного пользователя
to learning the problems solved by the administrators, developers or DevOps.
и перейти к изучению путей решения задач, выполняемых администраторами, разработчиками или DevOps.